Email: george8s@live.co.uk Mobile: 07975716496

Personal Statement

A highly motivated chemistry graduate with an exceptional academic record transitioning into a software development career. A full stack developer with experience using HTML, CSS, JavaScript- React/node.js/npm in the frontend, as well as MongoDB (Mongoose) and MySQL (Sequelize) for the backend. Produced a final project during the Code Nation course: https://github.com/gtinsley99/marvel-backend using React and Sequelize with a MySQL database. This is a

Marvel character website displaying characters with their power stats and comics they appear in. Features include persistent login, favouriting characters, seeing the most popular characters for all users and adding a jpg profile picture to your account (stored as a blob in the database). Hosted on Netlify and Render respectively.

Key Skills

- JavaScript React, Node.js and npm
- HTML and CSS
- MongoDB
- Mongoose ODM
- MySQL
- Sequelize
- GltHub and GitFlow
- Agile methodologies
- Express
- Deployment with Netlify and Render

Portfolio and GitHub

- Link to my portfolio: https://gt99-portfolio.netlify.app/
- Link to my GitHub account: https://github.com/gtinsley99

Education

Code Nation- Master: Software course July 2023-October 2023

Initially started with HTML, CSS and JavaScript practice such as this dice game:

<u>https://github.com/gtinsley99/dice_game</u>. Then used React with Node.js and npm, hosting on GitHub using gh-pages: https://github.com/gtinsley99/ToDoList</u>. Moved over to backend development using Mongoose and MongoDB: https://github.com/gtinsley99/booksAPI and MySQL and Sequelize:

<u>https://github.com/gtinsley99/cookies</u> . Gained experience giving presentations to a group of peers as well as having stand ups to manage the progression of the projects. Also gained experience using GtiHub and GitFlow to protect the main branch and minimise merge issues.

University of Sheffield September 2017- June 2020

Chemistry BSc: 1st

Fallibroome Academy September 2015- June 2017

A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Biology (A*), Chemistry (A)

Fallibroome Academy September 2010- June 2015

GCSE's: 2A*s, 8As, B

Email: george8s@live.co.uk Mobile: 07975716496

Employment

- Laboratory technician, Medicines Discovery Catapult
 November 2020- December 2021
 - Working in a state-of-the-art IC accredited laboratory to test patient samples for COVID-19
 - o Strict adherence to health and safety protocols as a Class 2 containment facility
 - Management of a lab room and staff for processing patient samples
 - o Extraction of the virus and preparation of the samples for RNA extraction
 - o Coordination with other lab rooms to optimise sample processing
- Graduate Chemist, Manchester Organics

April 2022-June 2022

- Synthesising molecular compounds for clients
- Strict following of health and safety protocol due to the often highly dangerous chemicals involved in the synthesis
- O Working either independently or in a team depending on the project
- Left the job due to a major accident occurring in the lab

Work Experience

• Chemistry undergraduate research scholarship

June 2019-July 2019

- Assisted a PhD student in research into the properties, synthesis and potential applications of polymers sensitive to oxidative accelerated hydrolysis
- Gained experience working independently to synthesise a monomer, inputting and analysing size distribution data, presenting the findings as a poster
- Performed DLS and GPC analysis on the synthesised polymer nanoparticles to obtain the size distribution of the nanoparticles
- Oxfam Shop assistant (volunteering)

July 2014-August 2014

Provided customer service as well as stock control

Awards

Achieved the bronze award for Duke of Edinburgh

September 2013-July 2014

• Completed the National Citizenship Service (NCS) programme

April 2014-May 2014